Greetings church family. Um, welcome to
Living Mana Online
Church. Uh, I'm glad that you are
worshiping with us today. And, uh, today
is going to be a pretty
somber message. Um, this is a discussion
that, um, has been long
overdue and we need to have a real talk
and that's what we're going to do today.
So, uh, put a one in the chat if you're
ready for this message. And if you're
not ready for this message, put a one in
the chat anyway because,
um, we we need to have this discussion.
So, we're going to pray and we're going
to get right into it. So, I want to
invite you to pray with me, um, and pray
for me. Heavenly
Father, Lord, I ask in a special way,
Lord, that you would please
speak, Lord, through this message.
Help us Lord to to face
um tough realities not for all of us but
for many of us Lord. Um please prepare
the hearts of all who say they love
you. And may conviction set in is our
prayer in Jesus name. Amen.
And so we are addressing today uh the
the
issue of how the SOP is causing great
harm to the
church. It's it's a somber issue and
it's an issue again that we must address
um because we are we are at a
crossroads. I want to invite you to turn
with me uh to 1st Samuel chapter 10.
We're going to put the slide up on the
screen. In 1st Samuel chapter 10,
beginning with verse
one, we're looking at the story of uh
Samuel being anointed. And the Bible
says um or rather Saul being anointed.
The Bible says in 1st Samuel chapter uh
10, 1st Samuel chapter 10 beginning with
verse one, then Samuel took a vial of
oil and poured it upon his head, that is
Saul, and kissed him and said, "It is
not because the Lord has anointed thee.
Or is it not because the Lord has
anointed thee to be captain over his
inheritance?"
So we see here that that Saul is
anointed and then the Bible says in
verse 10 of the same chapter that
shortly after Saul is anointed says when
they came through to the hill behold a
company of prophets met him that is Saul
and the spirit of God came upon him and
he
prophesied among
them. And so what I want you to note
here is that Saul after he is anointed
receives the spirit of prophecy. The
Bible says the spirit of God came upon
him and he prophesied. Verse 11. And it
came to pass when all that knew him
before before time saw
that. Behold, he prophesied among the
prophets. Then the people said one to
another, "What is this that is come unto
the son of Kish? Is Saul also among the
prophets? And so please note here, I
want you to put it put this in the chat.
Saul had the spirit of prophecy. And
hence we we we like to abbreviate it the
SOP, the spirit of
prophecy. And we know that for a time
Saul was was good with God. And then
we're introduced to a new character a
little bit later in the story whose name
is David. And we know that David um does
a mighty feat. He defeats
Goliath while Saul was afraid to fight
Goliath. Would not go out to fight him.
A and Saul had begun to take a turn for
the
worst. And and so after David defeats
Goliath, uh we're going to see here in
in 1st Samuel chapter 18 verse 6. 1st
Samuel chapter 18 verse 6. Let's go back
to the screen. And it says, "And it came
to
pass as they came when David was
returned from the slaughter of the
Philistines that the women came out of
all the cities of Israel singing and
dancing to meet King Saul with tabs,
with joy, and with instruments of
music." Verse 7, "And the women answered
one another as they played and said,
Saul has slain his thousands and David
his 10 thousands."
And Saul was very
wroth, and the saying displeased him,
and he said, "They have ascribed unto
David 10 thousands, and to me they have
ascribed but thousands. And what can he
have more but the kingdom?" And I want
you to notice verse nine. And Saul eyed
David from that day forward.
Saul eyed David. Now listen guys, every
time I read this verse that Saul eyed
David. I just have this picture in my
mind of like, you know, imagine the
camera just zooming in on one of Saul's
eyes and he's just eyeing David. And you
know, it it it's kind of a funny
picture, but it's also a sad
picture. Saul eyed David. You can
imagine that eye. that I became
evil. And and and this is this is where
Saul is beginning to to move away from
the spirit of
prophecy. And now Saul has
become
paranoid. Put that word in the chat for
me, please. Saul has become
paranoid. Instead of the spirit of
prophecy being upon him, it is now the
spirit of
paranoia. S O P. A different type of
SOP. Saul is now
paranoid of David. Y'all put a one in
the chat if you're
following. So, he moves from the spirit
of prophecy to the spirit of paranoia.
And I want you to notice uh uh in the
same chapter, next verse, very next
verse, verse 10, the Bible says, "And it
came to pass on the marorrow that the
evil spirit from God came upon Saul, and
he prophesied in the midst of the
house. And David played with his hand as
at other times, and there was a javelin
in Saul's hand." Now, let me ask y'all a
question. What is Saul about to do with
this javelin? What does this
signify? Saul is about to be begin a
course against
David. And and what Saul is going to do
is he's going to
begin, the text says that an evil spirit
came upon Saul and now Saul is going to
begin to persecute. Put that word in the
chat for me, please. Persecute David.
Meaning Saul went from the spirit of
prophecy to the spirit of
paranoia which ultimately led to the
spirit of
persecution. Persecution of one of his
own. If y'all with me so far, put a one
in the chat. So, let's talk about the
spirit of paranoia for a moment. And in
this spirit of paranoia that Saul began
to exercise, uh, he began to think
things about
David, things that were not true. But
nonetheless, he became
paranoid. And this paranoia began to
work all sorts of crazy thoughts in his
mind. David is out to kill me. David is
out to get me. David is out to take my
kingdom. And he begins to think all
these paranoid thoughts which ultimately
lead the spirit of paranoia SOP
ultimately led to the spirit of
persecution
SOP. Are y'all with me so
far? Now, now why have I used this as
the foundation of our message today?
Please come back with me and I want you
to notice remember something about Saul.
In the beginning of our story, we saw
that Saul was anointed. Put that word in
the chat for me, please. Saul was
anointed. So, please keep that in mind.
And I want you to notice with me now 1st
Samuel chapter 9 verse two. 1st Samuel
chapter 9 verse two. The Bible says of
Saul, "And he had a son whose name was
Saul, a choice young man and a goodly.
There was not among the children of
Israel a goodlier person than he from
his shoulders and upward. He was higher
than any of the people. So I want you to
note the stature of Saul, this anointed
one. Let me say it again. The stature of
Saul, this anointed one, this one that
was called goodlier than anybody else.
There was none goodlier than him.
Beautiful word there. Goodlier.
He was both goodlier and taller in
statute than anyone else. And he was an
anointed one. Put a one in the chat if
y'all are following me. He was an
anointed one. And if we begin to think,
man, who does this remind me of? Yes.
Yes. You would not be wrong for saying
it reminds me of Lucifer. Let's go back
to the screen. And I want you to note in
Ezekiel 28:14 where the Bible says of
Lucifer, "Thou art the anointed cherub
that coverth, and I have set thee so.
Thou was upon the holy mountain of God.
Thou has walked up and down in the midst
of the stones of fire. Thou was
perfect, goodlier than any other angel.
Thou was perfect in thy ways from the
day that thou was created till iniquity
was found in thee." So, so please note
here. In fact, let's just go to the next
slide very quickly. And I want you to
note Isaiah
14:13, where the Bible says, "For thou
hast said in thine heart," speaking of
Lucifer, "I will ascend into heaven. I
will exalt my throne above the stars of
God. I will sit also upon the upon the
mount of the congregation in the sides
of
north. I will ascend above the heights
of the clouds. I will be like the most
high." That's Isaiah chapter 14:es 13.
and 14. So please note with
me that
Lucifer, who was once an anointed
cherub, who was once perfect,
goodly if you
will, perfect in
statute, becomes
jealous of Jesus. He wants to sit in the
place of the most high. He wants to be
like the most high.
Now, why is this significant? Because
you'll remember that in the character of
David, David is introduced to
us as a shepherd who is watching his
father's flock, his father's
sheep, when an enemy rises up to
threaten the flock, and David defeats
that
enemy. Think with me, y'all. Think with
me of what Jesus did in heaven before
the earth was created. Now remember in
the story of David, the father, his
father sends his son to go check on his
brethren. He came unto his own, but his
own received him not. And you're going
to say, "Yes, yes, yes, pastor. David is
a type of Jesus, while Saul is a type of
Satan." Very good. Understanding that, I
want to now take you back to what
happened in heaven. And I want to share
something with you. Let me read this
definition for you for a moment. Come
with me back to the screen. And I want
to look at the word paranoia. Paranoia.
So the word paranoia, it literally means
a tendency on the part of an individual
or a group toward excessive or
irrational
suspiciousness and distrustfulness of
others. Did y'all get that definition?
an excessive or irrational
suspiciousness and distrustfulness of
others. Here's another definition.
Paranoid is an ad adjective used to
describe someone who has the mental
disorder paranoia, which is
characterized by
delusions and feelings of extreme
distrust. Don't trust
anybody. Suspicion and being targeted by
others. It can also refer to feelings or
to feeling extremely nervous and worried
because you believe that other people do
not like you or are trying to harm you.
All
right. So with this definition of
paranoia in mind and we're not talking
about now the clinical definition of
paranoia, we are talking about the
spiritual definition of paranoia, the
biblical definition of paranoia. So I'm
not dealing with people who are
clinically diagnosed as being paranoid.
That's not what I'm doing. That's not
what I'm talking about. We're talking
about biblically paranoid. Here's my
question for you right now.
Was Lucifer in heaven according to that
definition
paranoid? Did Lucifer begin to think in
his mind that God was up to something
that he was not up
to? Come on. Let's go now to what we
also call the spirit of prophecy. the
writings of the prophet that God gave to
this church, which I am unashamed to say
is a
prophet and has she is not the spirit of
prophecy, but she has the spirit of
prophecy because that's what all
prophets have. And so we say when
referring to her writings that they are
the SOP, the spirit of prophecy. So, let
me say to you right
now that I believe that God has gifted
our church with the spirit of prophecy.
But beloved, we also have a major issue
with a different type of
SOP. And y'all are going to see what I'm
saying in a moment. So, let's go back
and let's check out what the spirit of
prophecy has to say about Lucifer in
heaven. Let's go to the
screen. And here's what it says.
Patriarchs and Prophets, page 38.
Lucifer had presented the purposes of
God in a false light, misconstring and
distorting them to excite dissent and
dissatisfaction. He cunningly drew his
hearers on to give utterance to their
feelings. Then these expressions were
repeated by him when it would best or
when it was when it would serve his
purpose as evidence that the angels were
not fully in harmony with the government
of
God. While claiming for himself perfect
loyalty to God, he urged that changes in
the order and laws of heaven were
necessary for the stability of divine
government. thus while working to excite
opposition to the law of God and to
instill his own discontent, his own
paranoia, his own
distrust into the minds of angels under
him.
He ostensibly he was ostensibly seeking
to remove dissatisfaction and to
reconcile
disaffected angels to the order of
heaven while secretly fermenting discord
and rebellion. He with consumate craft
caused it to appear as his sole purpose
to promote loyalty and to preserve
harmony and peace. So let me ask you a
question again.
Was Satan distrustful when he had no
reason to be
distrustful? Was Satan suspicious? Was
Satan paranoid? Was Satan beginning to
think, "Yeah, God God is is trying to
hold stuff back from
me. God has a plan to keep me down."
Just as Saul became paranoid of David,
was Satan paranoid of Jesus in
heaven, was Satan beginning to watch
with an evil
eye Jesus's moves? What is God doing
now? What is he up to now? Just beloved,
listen to me. In the story of David and
Saul, we have a snapshot of what
occurred in heaven.
We see how deluded Satan became through
his own paranoia, through his own
distrust, through his own and he begins
to watch for
evil. Hold on, y'all. Hold on. Watch
this. Come back with me to the screen.
Ezekiel 28:16. Note what the Bible says
here.
By the multitude of thy merchandise,
they have filled the midst of thee with
violence, and thou hast sinned. That's
verse 16. Notice with me again, verse
18. Thou hast defiled thy sanctuaries by
the multitude of thine iniquities, by
the iniquity of thy traffic. Do y'all
see it on the screen? Let me read it
again. Ezekiel 28:16. By the multitude
of thy merchandise, they have filled the
midst of thee with violence, and thou
hast sinned. Thou hast defiled thy
sanctuaries. By the multitude of thine
iniquity, by the iniquity of thy
traffic. Let me ask you a question. Was
Lucifer
merchandising that which we which he had
become paranoid
about? Yes, indeed.
He began to merchandise to the other
angels his own paranoia, his own
distrust. And he began to put in them
the same spirit of paranoia. S O
P, the same spirit of
distrust
against angelic brethren.
The Bible says in Revelation 12:4,
Revelation 12:4, note with me, the Bible
says, "And his tail drew the third part
of the stars of heaven and did cast them
to the earth." Why is that significant?
According to Isaiah chapter 9:15, the
ancient and honorable, he is the head,
and the prophet that teacheth lies, he
is the tail. What did Lucifer
merchandise to onethird of the angels
that caused the angels to be swept away
by his tail? He was merchandising lies.
He was merchandising his own paranoia,
his own fears, his own worked up
imagination.
Notice again with me, notice again with
me, going back to the spirit of
prophecy, she continues to say,
"Lucifer went forth to diffuse the
spirit of discontent among the angels."
The spirit of what? Everybody put that
word in the chat for me, please. The
spirit of
discontent.
Discontent. For a time he concealed his
real purpose under an appearance of
reverence for God. He insinuated doubts
concerning the laws that governed
heavenly
beings, intimating that
angels needed no such restraint, for
their own wisdom was was a sufficient
guide. All their thoughts were holy. It
was no more possible for them than for
God himself to er this the exaltation of
the son of God as equal with the father
was represented as an injustice to
Lucifer. If this prince of angels could
but attain to his true exalted position,
great good would acrue to the entire
host of heaven. For it was his object to
secure freedom for all. Subtle
deceptions through the ws of Lucifer
were fast obtaining in the heavenly
courts.
Lucifer is
going insane in his
mind. His paranoia has taken
over. And now he's beginning to think of
all kinds of scenarios in which God is
unjust, in which the the the the
heavenly host, the heavenly government
is actually corrupt and they are doing
things behind the angel's
backs. Which brings me to my next
point. How did
Satan deceive and merchandise his
paranoia? He painted a false picture of
the
future. Let me say it again. He painted
a false picture of the future. In other
words, he presented a picture to
one-third of the angels that if we
continue to serve God in the way we are,
if we don't do something now, because
God is up to something, if we don't make
our move now, things in the future are
going to be bad. And so he now presents
a
counterfeit spirit of prophecy, a
counterfeit prophetic picture, one based
on self centered fear. If we don't do
something now, it's going to be very bad
for us in the future. Come back with me
to the screen. Notice what it says here.
He told them that both he and they had
now gone too far to go back and he would
risk the consequences because he would
never bow in survile worship. Angels, if
we if we repent, if we submit, it's
going to be serv worship from here on
out to the son of God. He claimed that
God would not forgive. And now they must
assert their liberty and take by force
the position and authority that was not
willingly given to them. In this way,
Lucifer, the lightbearer, who shared
God's glory, who stood next to his
throne by transgression, became Satan,
the adversary. Do y'all see this?
He now paints a picture of what will
happen if they don't act now. What will
happen if they don't fight now? What
will happen if they even think about
repenting? If they even think about
going back. No, it's going to be bad.
And this is all a self centered fear of
the future. Follow me y'all. I know
y'all thinking right now, oh, pastor's
about to kill. Just follow me. Don't
Don't think ahead. Stay with me in the
moment,
please. Let's keep reading. Let's keep
reading. The exaltation of the son of
God as equal to the father. In fact,
let's just here. Come on. Notice
Revelation 12:7. Notice Revelation 12:7.
The Bible says, "And there was war in
heaven. Michael and his angels fought
against the dragon, and the dragon
fought and his angels." Now, let me ask
you a question.
Is the devil and his angels now seeking
to persecute their fellow
angels? What are they attempting to do
in this
war? They are attempting to fight
against and dominate over their fellow
angels. In other words, beloved, the
SOP, spirit of paranoia,
ultimately leads to the spirit of
persecution. I want y'all to put that
formula in the chat for me,
please. The spirit of paranoia will
ultimately lead to the spirit of
persecution. Y'all got it? The spirit of
paranoia will always lead to the spirit
of persecution. Now, now that we have
set that groundwork, remember the
dragon and his angels
fought. The dragon had been spreading
lies, speaking lies with his mouth. And
what were those lies? We are being
unduly or unfairly treated when they
weren't. We are being persecuted when
they weren't. And the paranoia, the fear
that he was able to capitalize on to to
to to grab hold of these angels with
fear, the spirit of fear. I'm going to
come back to that. That self-centered
fear ultimately led to the spirit of
persecution.
Now, put a two in the chat if y'all
ready to go to the next
point because here we come to the next
point. You guys, are y'all ready for
this? Come with me back to the screen.
Revelation chapter 13 and verse 11.
Revelation
13:1. The Bible says here, "And I beheld
another beast coming up out of the
earth, and he had two
horns like a
lamb, and he spake as a
dragon." Now, let me ask y'all a
question. Let me ask you guys a
question.
If the
dragon in the beginning
became paranoid and then spread that
paranoia to one-third of angels to lead
them to believe that there was an enemy
threat that was
non-existent. And through that
non-existent enemy
threat lead
them to end up having the persecution.
Then would it be fair to
assume that this end time
beast that looks like a
lamb? So, so a lamb is docile, right? In
fact, come with me back to the screen. I
want you to notice Isaiah 53 verse verse
7, which says this. He was oppressed, he
was afflicted, yet he opened not his
mouth. He is brought as a
lamb to the slaughter and as a sheep
before her sharers is dumb. So he opened
not his mouth. Or how about this one?
Jeremiah 11 verse 19. But I was like a
lamb or an ox that is brought to the
slaughter. I knew not that they had
devised devices against me, saying, let
us destroy the tree with the fruit
thereof, and let us cut him off from the
land of the living that his name may not
be may be no more remembered. The lamb
is a docile creature.
It is easy to persecute a lamb. Could it
be possible that this beast in
Revelation 13:11, while appearing
docile, while while claiming docility,
while even claiming
persecution, could be
induced with the
spirit of
paranoia, which will ultimately lead to
the spirit of persecution. What do you
think? Could it be possible that the way
this lamblike beast that ultimately
speaks like a dragon, could it be
possible that the
persecution done by this lamblike beast
at the end of time is
done under the spirit of
paranoia? Let me let me show you what I
mean.
So for
example um just recently let's go back
to the screen um a new office has been
put in place uh in our government and
that office is the white house faith
office white house faith office. Let's
let's come back and
um let me ask
you so what is that office supposed to
do? It's supposed to stop, right? Or no
longer. Yeah. Supposed to
stop
the persecution of
Christians
here, the unfair and and
unjust treatment, the persecution of
Christians in America.
So let let's let's go back to the screen
in Christianity
today and this is uh
2024 uh the 50
countries where it is hardest to follow
Jesus in 2024. All right. So do you see
the slide on the screen?
This is from Christianity
today.
And in this
picture, in this
slide, it's going to discuss, can you
guys see it on the
screen? In this slide is going to
discuss what 50
countries are the hardest countries in
which it is to follow
Jesus. Same
article says this. Almost 5,000
Christians were killed for their faith
last year. Almost 4,000 were abducted.
Nearly 15,000 churches were attacked or
closed. And more than
295,000
29500,000 Christians were forcibly
displaced from their homes because of
their
faith. Let's keep
reading. And
uh there we go. When this list was first
issued in 1993, only 40 countries scored
sufficiently high to warrant tracking.
This year, 78 countries qualify.
And there you see the map, the countries
that
qualify for where it is really hard to
follow
Jesus, where it is really hard to be a
Christian, where Christians
are actually being persecuted. Now, let
me ask a question. Can you guys see
America on that map? Put a one in the
chat if you see America on that map. So
in this map, you know, the deeper the
red, the more the the the stronger the
persecution, stronger the
persecution. So note with me what
America looks
like. Check out this
article. There's the same map.
You see, America has no color on it. No
red, no orange, no color. That's
strange. It's not
strange. But you would think, you would
think, check this out, y'all. Uh, in
this next
slide from the magazine Relevant, this
is a Christian-based magazine. says
59% of American Christians say they are
persecuted, may not understand real
persecution. So, so let's talk for a
moment. Let's talk for a moment about
what
what Christians here in
America, right? And we understand what
the Bible calls apostate
Protestantism. What do we here in
America? What do Christians here in
America, the Christians who say, "Man,
we're under persecution here." And
because we're under persecution here,
we've got to get a hold of the
government because unless we get a hold
of the
government, things are going to get
really bad for Christians. And they're
already getting really bad.
They are try they are trying to cancel
Christmas. If someone doesn't stand up
and and and say something and do
something, what will become of us
next? Are y'all following what I'm
saying? They're trying to cancel
Christmas. Hey, they're trying to force
me to bake a cake. Cake
wars. In other countries, Christians are
dying. They are literally being
killed. Whereas here in America, check
this out, y'all.
The one
nation which is
prophesied to bring about the greatest
persecution that the world has ever
seen is the nation where Christians are
most free to follow their faith. And
yet, and yet we have
this, the devil is putting this spirit
of
paranoia into American Christianity
where if we
don't get a hold of the
government, we will be forced to bake
cakes for gay people. We will be forced
to
endure LGBTQ people getting
married. I I need y'all to understand
and I don't want to make light of this
like I I I'm trying to say look at
what's happening in these other
countries and here we are in America
arguing about cancel culture if we don't
do something America is going we're
going to be persecuted. I want y'all to
understand that the devil has created a
spirit of paranoia, placed it within
American Christianity to the point
where they are now like if we do not
take over the government, if we do
not if we do not take the reigns of
government and get our people in office,
then Christianity in America is going to
be forced.
to lose the culture wars. Culture wars.
You think they're fighting culture wars
in other countries where Christians are
actually being persecuted? Their homes
are actually being burnt
down. Beloved, we know that in Bible
prophecy, no such thing is going to
happen in America. We know that there's
not going to be a communist Marxist. We
know that from Bible prophecy. And yet
there are many of us among us now who
have bought into this
fear, this
paranoia that is the very thing that is
moving apostate
Christianity to become the persecuting
spirit that it is.
So, so what happens is we they are
creating this false prophecy which we
call
esquetology.
Esquetology. Let me let's go back to the
screen for a moment and um here's what I
want you to remember. I want you to
remember a a little acronym. Let's go to
the
screen. Please check this out.
Um, there we
go. All
right. False
esquetology appearing
real. The acronym is fear.
false
esquetology
appearing
real. Kind of like a false spirit of
prophecy. Isn't that
interesting? A false spirit of
prophecy based on
fear, false esquetology appearing
real. And it is this false esquetology
appearing real. if we don't do
something. In fact, let me go back and
I'll show you where Ellen White actually
says, "The teachings of religious
leaders have opened the door to
infidelity, to spiritualism, and to
contempt for God's law. And upon these
leaders rest a fearful responsibility
for the iniquity that exists in the
Christian world. Yet this very class put
forth the claim that the fastspreading
corruption is largely attributable to
the desecration of the so-called
Christian Sabbath and that enforcement
persecution y'all enforcement of Sunday
observance would greatly improve the
morals of society. This claim is
especially urged in America where the
doctrine of the true Sabbath has been
most widely
preached. Do y'all see this?
You know who's causing all this trouble
in
America? It's those enemies out there.
And unless we do something, unless we
take hold of the government, they are
going to destroy
America. And so the false esquetology
appearing real
fear is
embraced. And this is what leads, this
is what leads, go back to the screen to
Revelation
13:15. Revelation 13:15. And he had
power to give life unto the image of the
beast, that the image of the beast would
both speak, and cause that as many as
would not worship the image of the beast
should be killed. And he caus all all,
both small and great, rich and poor,
free and bond, to receive a mark in
their right hand or in their forehead.
In other words, beloved, it is the
spirit of paranoia. The the communists
are coming to get us. the the the
Marxists are coming to get us. The el
the homosexuals are coming to get us. It
is a spirit of paranoia that will lead
that will
lead to the spirit of
persecution just like it did in
heaven. All in the name of survival.
All based upon a self centered
fear. Jeremiah 12 verse 5 says this. If
thou has run with the footmen and they
have wearied thee, how then can thou
contend with horses? And if in the land
of peace were you trusted? The land of
peace. Y'all, that doesn't sound like
China to me. That doesn't sound like
Russia to me. Where is the land of
peace? If in the land of peace, wherein
you trusted they wear thee, they made us
wear
masks. They stopped us from going to
church for a few
months. The LGBTQ people did this.
They're getting married.
If in the land of peace wherein you
trusted, they wearied thee, how then
shalt thou do in the soiling of the
Jordan? And here's what Adam Clark says
on this comment on this on this verse.
If thou has run with the footmen, if the
smallest evils to which thou art exposed
cause thee to make so many bitter
complaints, how wil thou feel in the
course of the prophetic ministry, thou
shalt be exposed to much greater from
from enemies much more powerful. Footmen
may here be the symbol of common evil
events, horsemen of evils much more
terrible. If you sunk under small
difficulties, what will you do when the
great ones
come? Beloved, the way American
Christianity is
acting, there are people in other
countries who wish that the persecution
was they made me bake a cake.
But that's not happening in other
countries. Here we are in America, the
land of the
free, but embracing a fear false
esquetology appearing real.
And it's moving the Christian world to a
place now where they can blatantly look
at injustices that are going on and
literally not even bat an
eye because it's all for the greater
good.
So the name of this message was we have
a spirit of we have a sop problem in the
church. So come on let let let's go back
to the screen and I want you to notice
with me Revelation 12:1 17. Revelation
12:1 17. So the Bible says here, "And
the dragon was wroth with the woman and
went to make war with the remnant of her
seed, which keep the commandments of God
and have the testimony of Jesus Christ."
So we understand what this means now,
right? We know that the dragon is going
to turn the spirit of paranoia upon the
church, upon the woman. Are you put a
five in the chat if you're with me so
far, beloved? Because this is where this
message is
going. If the dragon
operated through paranoia in heaven,
which then led to
persecution, if he's doing it through
the lamblike beast that speaks as a
dragon, we know that when he ultimately
turns this wrath on the
woman to cause her to be persecuted, it
will be because of paranoia.
He will turn the paranoia against the
woman. The woman is a
cult. The woman is dangerous. The woman
is blasphemous. The woman is teaching
that that Satan is our sinbearer.
the woman uh uh uh does not believe in
in in in assurance of salvation. So you
you are hearing these things now and
doesn't it seem to you that these things
are becoming more and more common? Like
it's just like you go on YouTube and and
all these videos now it almost seems
like people know if they put our
Adventist occult, they're going to get
views. And so you can begin to see this
in the Adventist critics. Whoa. We can
see Satan turning the spirit of paranoia
against God's end time church as the
Bible prophesied. In fact, at the end of
time, we're going to be called all kinds
of things by the whole world. The spirit
of paranoia will be upon them. These are
the enemies of
God. These are the ones who are causing
the problems in the world. It is the
spirit of paranoia that is going to lead
to the spirit of persecution. Are you
with
me? So, so we we see these attacks
coming from outside the church. But
beloved, lo and behold, lo and
behold, could it be
possible that the devil is even
attacking the woman from the
inside? So that Even now on the inside,
the spirit of
paranoia is being nurtured in the
church. Yeah. Yes. Yes. Yes. We have an
SOP problem, church. And the SOP problem
that we have is the spirit of
paranoia, the spirit of
distrust, the spirit of
discontent, the spirit of the fear of
being deceived. We are so afraid of
being deceived that we're looking out
for all kinds of enemies to the point
where we no longer listen and follow the
spirit of prophecy. No, we've exchanged
the spirit of prophecy in the name of
the spirit of prophecy, but we are now
embibing in the spirit of paranoia.
We are now embibing in this spirit of
distrust among our own brethren and
we're mer this is being merchandised in
the
church where it is now popular and cool
and and the in thing and and the present
truth thing to be like yeah the church
is people just the church is The church
isn't the organization, it's the people.
Go look at what Ellen White said about
the organization of the Seventh Day
Adventist Church. Go look at what Ellen
White said about how God moved upon them
when the back after 1844 where
Adventists were fearful of organizing
because they looked at organization as
Babylon. And look at what the Lord
inspired the prophet to write about that
fear saying, "No, no, no, no. God
desires organization." The church is the
organization and the organization is the
church. It is one thing and the people
in the organization don't all make up
the church. But God has an organized
movement and now it's just flippant to
say, "Oh yeah, because why?" Because we
have we have gotten used to embibing in
the spirit of
paranoia. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, man. Yo, I'm
telling you, you know what they're
doing. You know what they're doing here.
You know what they're doing there. And
we're Look
what just as David as Saul eyed
David, we have
become bent on
eyeing other
people. We eye each. We eye. We're in
the same church. I'm eyeing you because
I think you're up to something evil. I
think it's up to something no good. I
think you're up to something corrupt in
our own
church. That evil
eye, it could be from you to the GC. It
could be from you to your elder. Oh man,
my elders, the elder, they they no good.
It could be from you to another member
of the church. She's up to no good. He's
up to no good. There something's going
on there. And and we embibbe in this
spirit of paranoia, this spirit of
fear, selfentered fear. Come on, let's
read a couple quotes here. We almost
done. Let's read a couple quotes here.
Check this out,
y'all. All who wish, you see it on the
screen. All who wish to draw off from
the body of
Christ. There we go. All who wish to
draw off from the body will have
opportunity. Something will arise to
test everyone. The great sifting time is
just before us. The jealous and the
faultf finding. Listen y'all, we have
people and ministries based on faultf
finding. Faultf finding
ministries who are watching. Let's go
back. who are watching for
evil. Highlight that y'all. Who are
watching for evil will be shaken
out? Watching for evil, pastor. But
aren't we supposed to watch for evil?
Beloved, y'all need to understand what
she's saying here because she says the
faultf finding. That sounds like a
righteous thing. Man, you know what? I
caught the fault there. I see what that
person did wrong there. I caught the
fault. She says the faultf finding. And
those that are watching for evil, the
evil eye, I'm watching. I saw what they
did. I saw what they see what the
leadership is doing there. Those who are
watching for evil will be shaken out. I
didn't say that. The spirit of prophecy
said that those who have the spirit of
paranoia in the place of the spirit of
prophecy will be shaken out. Let's keep
reading. Let's keep reading. Let's go
back to the
screen. The time of peril is now upon
us. It can no longer be spoken of as in
the future. And the power of every mind
sanctified to the master's work is to be
employed not to be not hedged up not
hedged up the way before the message God
sends to his people but to labor
unitedly in preparing a people to stand
in the great day of God. It is not the
inspiration from heaven that leads one
to be
suspicious, watching for a chance and
greedily seizing upon it to prove that
those brethren who differ from us in
some interpretation of scripture are not
sound in the faith.
watching
greedily to seize upon
something to
prove, see they're not really faithful.
See, they're not really the re See,
they're not really the the remnant of
the remnant. Beloved, it is the same
spirit of Satan in
heaven that leads
us to turn our weapons upon the church
or to turn our weapons upon others in
the church in the
name of present
truth. Let's go back. Y'all need to see
more of this. Watch this. Let's go
back. There is danger that this course
of action will produce the very result
assumed. And to a great degree, the
guilt will rest upon those who are
watching for evil.
The spirit of
paranoia, the watching for evil, the
sharpness of eyesight to detect a moat
in another's eye is evidence that you
have a beam in your own eye. Everything
may not be done in just the way you
suppose that that that you would have
done it. But if you were in mind and
heart and character submitted to the
control of the spirit of God, you would
see that the Lord's way and his thoughts
are much above your way and your
thoughts as the heavens are higher than
the earth. Here's another
one. You have strengthened a spirit of
evil speaking of watching for
evil. Let me say it again, y'all.
Sometimes as
Adventists, we we pride ourselves on
watching for
evil and everything becomes
evil. If a brother is preaching and
happens to do say something like, "I
love you." They'll be like, "Look at
this picture
thumbnail. Worshiping the devil."
Really, y'all? Really?
We can get so caught up in the evil eye
that
everything becomes evil. And when
everything becomes evil, beloved, to
you, it is an evidence that the enemy of
God is working through you because that
same spirit of suspicion is now turned
against everybody. And you're looking
you're looking for something to prove
that you are better than everyone else
around you. You are truly the remnant of
the remnant because you and only
you. You're trying to find a way to
justify
why God loves you better than everybody
else. This is why Ellen White warns
against this watching for evil. Watching
for evil. Come on, let's go back to the
screen. We're almost there, y'all. We're
almost done. I I hope you understand now
the serious SOP problem, spirit of
paranoia, where everybody is evil and
everything is evil and they're out to
get you and the church is the and the
conference is this and the GC is this
and all this evil. It's just so
overwhelming. All in the name of
righteousness. Come
on. Here's the bomb. Here's the bomb,
y'all. Listen to the
bomb. Satan contrives through evil
angels to form an alliance with
professedly pious
men and thus to leaven the church of
God. Fallen men and fallen angels are
through apostasy in the same
confederacy league to work against good.
They unite in a desperate companionship.
Satan knows that if he can induce men as
he induced angels to join in rebellion
under the guise of servants of
God, he will have in them his most
successful allies in his enterprise
against
heaven under the name of godliness. He
can inspire them with his
own. Put that word in the chat for me
you
guys. With his own
what? Accusing spirit and charge them
with evil. They are his trained
detectives.
Detectives. I was researching and I
discovered I discovered how wicked our
church. I discovered how how wicked our
leadership is. And you know what's
crazy, you guys? All kinds of offshoot
movements, all kinds of 7day Adventist
offshoot movements are taking the
opportunity to be like, "And here's why
the church is an apostasy because they
believe in the Trinity now." See that?
And that's why all this other stuff is
happening.
anything that they're clinging on to,
any any
any hobby, anything that they, okay,
this is my thing and here's why the
church is an apostasy because they don't
agree with me on this thing. You guys,
it doesn't matter what the thing is.
Please understand
that. You're seeing this attack on the
woman from outside the church and from
inside the church. And the one thing
they all have in common is an attack on
God's movement.
And I would just say we need to be very
careful, very
careful. It might be the popular thing
to do. It might be the popular thing to
do among our particular
audiences, but you guys, your audiences
can't save
you. The people who follow you can't
save you. The people who cheer you on in
what you're doing can't save you.
the people in your church who who are
backing you up. So, so, so yeah, go
fight against, you know, the pastor or
go fight against the elders or go fight
against these people in the church
because they can't save
you. Be very careful you all. Saul
thought he was doing
good. Saul thought he was right in his
accusations. Come on, let's go back to
the to the slide. Let me finish reading
the quote.
under the under the name of godliness he
can inspire them with his own trait
accusing them accusing spirit his own
accusing spirit and charge them with
evil are his trained detectives their
work is to create
feuds to make charges which create
discord and bitterness among
brethren that's their
work. Don't come at me with who you
talking about, pastor. I'm just saying
look at the fruit. I don't care who it
is.
If the work is causing dissension is the
if the work is to create discord and
bitterness among brethren to set tongues
in active service to Satan to seow seed
of dissension by watching for
evil and speaking of that which will
create discord.
Go
argue with Ellen
White. You can't argue with her because
she's in the
grave.
Beloved, we have an SOP problem. And
what I want you to understand is that an
SOP problem, a a problem of paranoia
will ultimately always lead to a spirit
of
persecution. Listen, listen. Revelation
19:10, listen to what the Bible says
here. Revelation 19:10. The Bible
says, uh, "And I fell at his feet, uh,
to worship him." There we go. I fell at
his feet to worship him, and he said
unto me, "See thou do it not. I am thy
fellow servant and of thy brethren that
have the testimony of Jesus. Worship God
for the testimony of Jesus is the spirit
of prophecy. Meaning the spirit of
prophecy is the testimony of Jesus.
Jesus is testifying to us of his own
word. And his testimony is he tells us
don't fear. Perfect love casts out fear.
His testimony is I'm telling you what is
coming to pass. So don't get paranoid.
Don't get off track about, oh, this is
going to happen and this is going to
happen. Don't start getting paranoid.
Don't start buying into the narratives
that you're watching. Don't start buying
into this whole, oh, the the new Do you
know? Do you know? Listen to me,
y'all. Do you
know that this whole United Nations is
evil? Do you know where that came
from? That did not come from Bible
prophecy, y'all. The whole idea of
United Nations being evil and and and
and the United Nations going to do this
and that that comes from a Sunday
Christian version of Bible prophecy. Go
pick up some of those conspiracy books
like uh the the the New World Order 666.
You know, y'all may have remembered
those books that came out in the 80s.
And all of those books unanimously were
talking about how the UN is evil and how
they're going to bring in this Marxist,
communist, anti-Christian, anti-godly.
And beloved, when I hear Adventists
talking about the evils of the UN,
what where is the
UN in Bible prophecy? I didn't know the
Bible prophecy talked about an
organization called the United
Nations. Really? An organization called
United Nations going to do X, Y, and Z?
The Bible speaks about Rome and it
speaks about apostate Protestantism and
that these two powers will will will
will embrace the whole world.
This idea of the United Nations and and
the coming new world order where the
United Nations is running things,
beloved, that is Sunday
prophecy. Yes, Daniel chapter 2 talks
about the breakdown of Rome and all
those things, but Daniel chapter 2 does
not talk about an organization called
the United
Nations. And so many of us are just
swerving into these this
this what is not prophecy, what is not
biblical prophecy. And we don't even
know that we're mingling we are
mingling the wine of Babylon, their
false prophecies, and working it into
our own prophecies. And what we get is
something deluded to where to today we
don't even want to talk about project
2025. We just want to downplay that all
day long and let's talk
about something else. Let's talk about
the pope. But let's not talk about
Christian nationalism.
The Bible says in 1 John chapter 4:17,
"Herein is our love made perfect that we
may have boldness in the day of
judgment, because as he is in the world,
so are we." There is no fear in love,
but perfect love cast out fear. Beloved,
we should have no reason to be
paranoid. We should have no reason to be
paranoid. We should fear God, not be
paranoid. And that's what's happening.
We are we're embracing the
paranoia of apostate Protestantism and
it's coming into our church. So now
we're just as apostate Protestantism is
saying our government is corrupt. So now
we have Adventists saying our government
is corrupt. We've got
to you
know Yeah.
Fear
blinds. Fear
blinds. The Bible says in Mark 4:40,
Jesus speaking to his disciples on the
boat, he said unto them, remember that
whole storm thing? Remember that they
were afraid. He said unto them, why are
you so fearful? How is it that you have
no faith? Fear eliminates faith.
Fear eliminates
faith. So when you're fearing, you
become
blind to what God has said is going to
you you begin to lose lose that that
spiritual eyesight, that spiritual
vision. And now in acting out in
paranoia, you're beginning to see
everything and everyone around you is
evil. Everything is corrupt. Everything
is evil.
And man, do we have a problem with
this at 7th Day
Adventist. May God help
us to get rid of the
SOP, the spirit of
paranoia, which will ultimately lead to
the spirit of persecution. We will be
right there with the whole world,
persecuting the people we once stood
with. That's where this will lead to.
And may God help us to embrace the
actual spirit of prophecy. May God help
us to embrace what God has said is
coming, to embrace the testimony of
Jesus. And to pray, Lord, create in me a
clean heart. Renew in me a right spirit.
Help me not to have this spirit of
paranoia, which will ultimately lead to
the spirit of persecution. Help me not
to to to watch for evil.
Change my heart,
God. Beloved, this sermon is not about
closing a blind eye to evil. Oh, you
know what? You see something that is
that is obviously wrong and you don't
see anything. That's not what I'm
talking about. I'm talking about the
spirit of par paranoia. I'm talking
about the spirit of accusation. And
beloved, as long as as we have that
spirit of paranoia against our
own, the spirit of prophecy
says you will be shaken
out. You will, not you might, you will
be shaken out.
May we learn to watch for Jesus and not
watch for
evil. May we
learn to watch for
Jesus and
not for
evil. Yes, beloved, we need watchmen on
the wall. Watchmen who will watch when
the sword is coming.
When the sword is coming
from outside because that's where the
sword is coming
from. God is not sending swords inside
his
church. As feeble and defective as his
church may be, it is still the apple of
his
eye. All right, y'all. We're going to go
to our last slide. This is our last
slide, and this may be the most
important one. going to share
tonight. Look at what it
says. The first thing recorded in
scripture history after the fall was the
persecution of Abel. And the last thing
in scripture, prophecy, is the
persecution against those who refuse to
receive the mark of the beast.
We should be the last people on the
earth to indulge in the slightest degree
the spirit of persecution against those
who are bearing the message of God to
the
world. This is the most terrible feature
of
uncristlikeness. Listen to this y'all.
that was manifested that has manifested
itself among us since the Minneapolis
meeting. She's talking about
1888. And she's talking about the the
the the the church or the the people in
the church turning their swords on one
another. You
guys, we have enough persecution that is
going to be coming from without the
church.
to be
engaged in persecuting in the church in
turning our swords on one another in the
church. She says the very first thing in
scripture is a persecution of Abel by
his
brother. The last thing in scripture is
a persecution of God's people by the
world. And then she says, the last thing
we need to do, put it back up on the
screen. I need you to see this
SOP. The last thing she says, we should
be the last people on the earth to
indulge in the slightest degree of the S
spirit O
of P
persecution against those who are
bearing the message of God to the world.
God has not called
us to bear a
message to anybody else but the
world. But beloved, when we turn our
swords on one
another, when we when we begin to turn
our swords on the church, oh, the church
is corrupt. Oh, the leadership is this.
Oh, the general conference. Oh, oh, the
church is is no longer the organization.
It's the
people. We are exhibiting the very thing
that the actual spirit of prophecy warns
us
against. My prayer, my prayer, our
prayer should be that as a
church, we can stop turning our weapons
on ourselves.
We can stop with the spirit of
suspicion. We can stop trying to watch
for evil to see who is and who isn't and
begin to focus on the mission God has
called us to focus on, which is the
preaching of the three angels messages
to the world.
May God help us to
reject the SOP, the spirit of paranoia,
the spirit of uh uh um of controversy,
the spirit of
conspiracy. May God help us to
reject the spirit of persecution.
May God help us to reject the spirit of
pride. May God even help us to reject
the spirit of politics that has entered
into the church that is now calling the
three angels messages simply political.
May God help us to embrace the actual
spirit of prophecy and teach what we
have always believed and direct our
message to who it needs to be directed
to. Lord, create in me a clean heart.
create in us clean hearts that we're no
longer
looking watching for evil in other
people ready to rejoice over the evil
that we see ready to broadcast the evil
that we see ready to to to to say see I
told
you Lord help us to reject the spirit of
paranoia the spirit of
persecution the spirit of pride.
Heavenly
Father, Lord, we thank you for speaking
to us today.
Lord, please rid your church of this
counterfeit spirit of pro, spirit of of
h of paranoia, spirit of uh persecution
and even a false spirit of prophecy
where we have taken on the prophecy of
the world, taken on the prophecy of
apostate
Christianity and mingled it with the
genuine
truth. Please
Lord heal us. We are Leodysia for a
reason. Heal us Lord that we that we may
be about your business. This is my
prayer in Jesus name. Amen. Man, I want
to thank you.